Crypto did kind of arouse some very primal feelings amongst a lot of people.
Well, it really started as the learning curiosity thing.
They mostly didn't understand it.
We just started hearing about this Bitcoin stuff and we're like,
wow, what is this?
It could really someday lead to radical changes in our business.
Okay, good morning, everyone.
I'm very excited to be here with Abby Johnson, CEO of Fidelity.
Welcome, Abby.
>> Thank you, it's great to be here.
>> I've been hearing from so many folks in this room how excited they are to hear from you.
So we're excited the moment is here.
So let's jump right into it.
So as you know, Abby, I have a background in traditional finance.
I came from the New York Stock Exchange when I joined A16Z Crypto.
And I know how hard it was back in the day to try to get a big
institutional financial institution into crypto.
But you did it early at Fidelity almost a decade ago.
You got Fidelity into crypto.
Tell us why you did it and how you did it.
>> Yeah, well, it really started as kind of a learning curiosity thing.
I mean, one of the things we try to do at Fidelity is really build a learning and
a curiosity kind of oriented culture.
So me and a bunch of people, like we just started hearing about this Bitcoin stuff and
we're like, wow, what is this and how does it work?
And none of us really could answer the question very clearly.
So we just started these regular conversations where let's try to understand this and see,
of course, back then when it first few years of it coming out.
And this would have been kind of around 2013-ish.
>> Very early days.
>> When we were at the 12, 13, we were really just talking about it and saying like,
is this even real?
Because if it's real, we want to know.
And if it's not, then move on to something else.
Anyway, pretty quickly, a group of very senior people,
me, a couple of business people and probably a bunch of people from our tech teams.
We looked at this and we looked at it and we thought, this looks real.
I mean, this is something going on here.
And we're going to start brainstorming about where it might go.
Because it could really someday lead to radical changes in our business.
And wouldn't that be interesting and exciting?
And we started brainstorming on use cases.
And we came up with a list of 52 use cases that we thought would be potentially exciting.
And we sent them out around the organization.
We sent people out to go investigate them and see if any of them would work.
Anyway, it turns out one of them worked.
And it was actually the simplest one.
And it was actually the thing that kind of, I think, put us on the map in those early days.
And somebody had suggested that since there was a lot of new wealth that was being created
by Bitcoin that there were a lot of people who wanted to use that newly found wealth
to make charitable deductions and to make charitable contributions.
And we have this thing called the charitable gift fund, which is a donor advised fund.
So we arranged to be able to accept donations in Bitcoin.
So to me, at the time, I thought this was a massive disappointment.
Not because it was a bad thing.
It was actually accepted and welcomed by the marketplace.
But the actual business, all we did was take people's crypto into our donor advised fund
and sell it and make it easy for them to be able to give away.
So no one else would have accepted it back in 2020.
Well, that was the big issue is that nobody else wanted to do it.
And I felt like this isn't very exciting.
But I think it did get us frankly credibility in the ecosystem of crypto and we met a lot
of people.
And at the same time, we were kicking off our own mining operations.
And I felt very strongly that if we were going to do this, we were going to do it from the
ground up kind of away.
And that meant being active in mining.
And we ran the numbers like everybody else.
And mining is actually a pretty attractive business.
It turned out to be probably the highest, single highest R or R business that we've had.
Well, if you started mining crypto in 2013, you did okay, yeah.
But it took a long time for that to be appreciated.
In fact, people tried to shoot down my initial proposal that we invest $200,000 to buy some
of those early ant miners.
And paid off.
Yeah.
Anyway, that was the start of it.
Great.
And then what was the evolution from there?
How did you get into enabling customers to trade Bitcoin and ETH, et cetera?
Well, so we continued with those use cases, most of which have never materialized.
But that's okay.
They were ideas.
They were ways for us to explore and learn.
And we didn't.
I mean, the way I thought things would go has turned out to be so totally different.
And in fact, the first real business, customer facing business that we launched was our custody
business.
And if you think about the nature of the custody business, I mean, custody is kind of like
the world's oldest, one of the world's oldest business.
You're taking somebody else's assets and holding it for them.
Initially, that struck me as so anti-crypto.
I mean, it kind of went against the grain of what I thought it was all about.
But then we had a lot of demand for custody services from independent advisors, many of
whom had people in the crypto business as their clients.
And people who were early holders of crypto were interested, I assume, in doing things
that lots of people do around planning for your survivors to be able to enjoy your assets
when you're gone, and you have to have a custodian to do that.
So we got into the custody business, and that really got, that was very foundational.
And I came to appreciate it.
One of my crypto colleagues started talking about how fidelity was really uniquely positioned
to be a bridge player.
So somebody who, an organization that would transcend tradFI and defi, and custody was
going to be an important part about that.
So it took me a little while, but I came to appreciate that point of view, and we went
into the custody business, and lots of independent advisors wanted to come to us as an increasing
number of their clients were coming to them with their Bitcoin and saying, "I need help
holding this and planning for the future of this asset in the context of my total state."
So that really got us in, and going in terms of serving customers, it put a lot of pressure
on us to build security, and as a traditional financial services player, we are all over
cyber security, traditional security, holding other people's money is the core, at the core
of what we do.
So something we, I think, was a really good challenge for the organization, and we built
a very deliberate, clear, and robust security system around our custody offering.
And I think, again, that helped us to continue to build credibility in the ecosystem.
And it's gone on from there.
So we now have crypto embedded in multiple parts of the organization.
I think that was really key towards being able to cultivate ideas.
We have ideas that come from different perspectives.
Our custody business now, thanks to the Genius Act, sits alongside our traditional brokerage
business as part of that business.
We have a digital assets management business, which is part of our asset management business,
and that is oriented around building investment offerings for people.
And so that's where we launched our ETPs out of, and they continue to have a long pipeline
of ideas of things that we would like to be able to bring to market with time.
But we also do other creative crypto things, both in our incubator organization, in our
tech R&D lab, so we've got stuff sprinkled around.
Well, you mentioned the Genius Act, perfect segue, to the next topic.
So obviously, this has been a huge year for crypto on the policy front.
We at A16C Crypto, along with so many in the crypto industry, have been fighting for years
for regulation, clarity from DC.
We finally got it, Genius.
We're still down there fighting for market structure, but there's still more.
There's more work to be done, but we've accomplished a lot.
So how does having regulatory clarity now with the Genius Act, how does that impact
fidelity and its customers?
The atmosphere, you know, prior to the current environment, there was, you know, back for
a while when crypto was small, you know, it didn't really get a lot of attention, and
I think a lot of people thought, oh, kind of it's that crazy cookie technology thing,
you would go to Washington and people would kind of look at you like sideways a little
bit.
Like, why are you talking about that?
You didn't understand it, or they didn't like it.
Yeah, well, they mostly didn't understand it, and then I think after a while when they
kept hearing about something, they didn't understand that, perversely made them not
like it, and the fact that it continued to grow.
And then you started to have these negative antibodies come out, and where things exist
existing, either existing, and in many cases, dated regulations started being turned around
and used against crypto, which, you know, probably wasn't ever going to stick, but it
was, you know, it made everything unpleasant, to say the least.
And I think for us, as an established player, we're in the position where we've got a core
business, and we've got commitments to our existing customers, and while we have lots
of customers who were saying, hey, I'd like to do crypto, in fact, we did a number of
studies on this, and took, kept track of how many customers called us and said, when is
fidelity going to do crypto, because I'm kind of thinking about it, but I have most of my
financial relationship with you, so I'd like to do it with you, or I'm kind of waiting
for fidelity to do it, because I don't really want to do it somewhere else, and we actually
had a number of people in the organization, this was really spectacular, who took it upon
themselves to raise their hand and say, I want to help with this, so we had a cadre
of reps, which we formally organized, just really because of their spontaneous willingness
to want to tackle this, who would take phone calls from people who were calling and wanting
to talk about, primarily Bitcoin at the time.
So we started doing these foundational things to try to keep everything warm while we hoped
that the regulatory environment would evolve, and of course it didn't just evolve, it kind
of swung the other way, so that's been exciting to catch up with.
So exciting, so you fidelity recently put out a report on stablecoins, which we thought
was great, and now we have the Genius Act, what do you find most interesting and promising
about stablecoins?
Is everyone talking about stablecoins?
Yeah, so I have to say my first reaction to stablecoins was a little back, I don't know
how many years ago, it was a little like the custody business, like isn't this kind of
the opposite of this, I'm not totally sure, but then once I really started to realize
how we were uniquely positioned to operate in this bridge space, I got all in on the
stablecoin, and so this has been exciting, and I think to the extent that there are lots
of people that do more in this space, I think that's great.
I would say we fought and spoke up quite vocally for quite a period of time to advocate for
paying interest on stablecoins, and this was very hotly debated internally, because we
were lying in the sand, this is what we do, when people give us money, we either show
them capital appreciation or pay them interest, at our core, we're an investment organization.
We always want to give people more money back than they gave us, so the idea that we would
take their money and hold it but not give them anything back, or have no intention, it
just fights with our values, and so up until the very end, we were fighting for interest.
At the end of the day, I weighed in and it felt to me like, frankly, it risked not getting
it done if we didn't concede that point, so with a lot of disappointment, I would say
we conceded that point, and anyway, it got done, which was great, so the next question
was what's the workaround for this, because we don't like this, so I think we've come
up with a pretty good workaround.
We recently launched an on-chain tokenized money market fund, and it pays the same kind
of yield as our traditional money market fund, which has historically been top of the charts
for the industry, so it's designed to be interoperable with a stablecoin, so the idea is that you
can hold your money, and the tokenized money market fund earn the most competitive liquid
yield that is available in the marketplace and flip into a stablecoin.
That's great, that's great.
Love hearing the evolution.
So trying to get the best of both worlds, it didn't quite happen how I thought.
Yeah, it was so controversial within the banking industry, but love how you viewed it the right
way.
So we put out our state of crypto report yesterday, we do this report annually, state of crypto,
and one of our conclusions was that this has been the year of institutional adoption
of crypto.
2025 is the year of institutional adoption, and I've spent the past year with our go-to
market team meeting with big financial institutions, including Fidelity, we met with your team,
and the one thing we kept hearing from a lot of organizations was they wanted to get into
crypto, but they had this dilemma of build versus buy.
Do we build the technology, or do we buy it?
Yeah.
And we talked through that a lot with folks.
How do you make that determination?
This is a very consistent theme in our organization.
It's either build versus buy, sometimes it's build versus buy versus partner.
And so we are more inclined to build compared to other similar kinds of financial institutions
to ourselves, but you can't build everything.
So you have to make a calculated bet on where the point of strategic differentiation is
going to be, and figure out how to one way or another, make sure that you have your fingers
on the controls of that, because that's really what gives you longevity.
Right.
So we have a lot of builders in this room who would love to partner with Fidelity.
What advice would you give to them as to how to go about that?
Yeah.
So we've got, there's a couple other people from Fidelity here.
We love to hear from people.
We love to have people in to visit.
We've got a very robust and active bits and blocks club in Fidelity.
We've got 4,500 members of that club.
We host a lot of events where we bring people in and cultivate a lot of networking.
These are people who work in this area, but also people who work in any job in Fidelity
and was allowed to join, just, you know, if you're interested.
We also have regular forums with senior management where we bring people in from the outside
to listen to what they're up to, where there might be general interest, even though there
isn't a clear, specific stated interest.
And then, of course, within our operating groups, I mentioned, we're always hosting things.
So I think it's all very circumstantial to try to answer that question, but we've had
a number of partnerships where we've worked with people and the whole nature of the crypto
world is for everybody to do their part and connect to each other.
So we want to continue to make sure that those conversations stay super active.
There's no -- we don't have a prescription in our organization of, you know, this is
the do's and don'ts of partnering with us.
I think we're a little more flexible than that.
You being here is a good first step, I think, for them.
So as we said, we have a room full of founders here.
They're all trying to build the next great company.
And in your own journey as a company leader, president and CEO for nearly a decade, what
were the biggest lessons you learned in your evolution as a leader?
I've learned so many lessons along the way, you know, stay curious, keep learning.
I mean, I feel like if I'm not learning, I'm not doing my job.
You know, in terms of running an organization and building culture, that's something that
continues to be a process and reinforced.
I mean, some of the things that I do is we have a lot of mandatory mobility in our organization
where we make people move around and do different jobs.
We don't let people sit in the same job for too long.
And I've found that to be incredibly valuable because it makes people develop different perspectives.
And if you don't actively work to make sure that you're developing different perspectives,
you tend to kind of calcify in your views.
So I think that's been really helpful.
We've done a lot of work around cultivating an environment where we want people to bring
bad news forward faster.
I always tell people, don't bore me with the good news, doesn't give me anything to do.
So that takes a lot of work to actually put that into action.
Right.
Absolutely.
Is there anything that you know now that you wish you had known back then when you were
starting out?
Oh, well.
Okay.
There are many things.
What's one?
What's one thing?
You know, trust your instincts.
I mean, you know, everyone has that inner voice that's gotten them to where they are
now, follow that inner voice.
Okay.
Good.
Very good advice.
All right.
So we're going to turn to questions now.
Q&A.
We've got a lot of eager folks in the audience who want to ask you some questions.
So let's kick it off.
For folks in the audience, please try to keep the questions brief so we can get as many
in as we can.
Hi, everyone.
Abby, thanks.
I'm ex-IDO, you actually started the IDO Colab on crypto in 2015.
So Fidelity started that group in 2015, and thank you for, you know, helping this industry
forward.
I guess one thing that's been interesting is like yesterday, there was a lot of talk
about how genius unlocks stablecoins and institutional adoption, but also the market
structure bill is coming, right?
Curious like what your thoughts are on what that might unlock if it passes this year,
like next year.
Looking ahead.
So our team is very engaged with the market structure bill.
I feel like every time I get an update on it, everything's completely changed.
I think that's an accurate assessment.
And so I actually told people, maybe I don't need so frequent updates, wait until it's
getting up.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, I want to start talking before it's signed, but
it needs to, it needs to find a few points of consensus.
So I'm kind of waiting on that, but we, our team is, we have a team that's very close
to it, and I'm sure they would, if they're not already connected, would love to connect.
Okay.
Who else?
For everything you've done in crypto, in the kind of crypto native community, there's
a sense that, oh, all of finance is going to be rebuilt.
And then from scratch on these new rails, and then maybe in more of the tradfi, sometimes
in the past we used to hear people say, this thing's not even going to happen, right?
And then there's a middle ground, which is tradfi adopts these new technologies and
integrates them.
Which one of those two paths, not even considering the one where it doesn't happen, but is it
going to be completely rebuilt, or is there kind of an evolution of it?
Well, there, I think there's zero chance that it's not happening because it is happening,
which is great.
You know, where I started with the 52 use cases a decade ago was more towards your first
scenario.
You know, how can this replace a lot of what we have in our system?
Because if you think about the world of tradfi right now, I mean, it's the most complicated
web of basically reconciliation processes, and it's really kind of scary.
If you step back and look at it, nobody would ever build anything like that.
It's just something that evolved organically over decades and people used the best available
technology for the thing that they were building today.
But the first things that they built were built on the technology that was available
then.
And because everybody's so interconnected, you're kind of caught at that lowest common
denominator of what now would be considered by most people, pretty primitive technology.
So there's a real kind of existential challenge for the industry, because I think at least
some of the bigger players would like to upgrade the broader infrastructure a little faster.
But the industry is a democratic place and there's a lot of small players who just don't
have the wherewithal to participate in that kind of upgrade.
So I don't really even think it's a debate.
It's going to be that middle ground that you said it's got to be an evolutionary process.
And it'll be some combination of competitive forces and regulatory standards that will
kind of push it kicking and screaming along.
Right now, I personally feel more drawn to things that offer us as a company the opportunity
to do things that we haven't done before, and to try to chart new courses and create
new opportunities for our customers that we haven't been able to offer in the past.
And so I think, you know, the thing that I, one thing I learned you asked me, what have
I learned from, you know, 10 years ago, I think if I had learned, you know, how I didn't fully
appreciate how slow change, really, in our traditional business is because there's just
so many forces that keep everybody kind of together and tight doing what they've always
been doing.
Change is not easy.
No, it's, yeah, it's tough, yeah, there's a, there's a tremendous amount of inertia
in financial services.
And it's perversely because it's so interconnected.
Yep, yep, that makes sense.
Okay, another question.
Thank you for joining us.
And also, thank you for, you know, bringing legitimacy to this space, all the way back
to 2013.
I still remember fondly those days at MIT, where, you know, most of my colleagues thought
I was crazy looking at this, but then fidelity came to our sessions and our meetings, and,
you know, people started wondering, okay, fidelity is here.
Nothing must be happening.
My question for you is about Bitcoin.
You've seen different asset classes emerge and have developed, you know, new instruments.
Where do you think Bitcoin is going next?
And it's not a question about price.
It's more a question about where does it fit in the landscape of everything you're offering.
Yeah.
Thank you.
So I don't know if it's because I started early or, I don't know, maybe as I get older,
I'm just kind of old fashioned, but like, I kind of like Bitcoin.
I don't own tons of coins, but I own Bitcoin.
And I think it will continue to play a role in the savings hierarchy of lots of people.
And it's, it is the gold standard, so to speak, you know, in the crypto world.
And it's been around, and it's solid, and it's persisted, and it's a good system.
So I'm long-term, very comfortable, and I think that that will continue to be something
that we will factor into our thinking and our quest to provide options for our customers.
And I'd like to be able to be one of the people that makes it, continues to make it
a little more accessible, because for all of the genius that went into designing Bitcoin,
it probably could have used some ideal resources, maybe, to help, help more people engage with
it sooner.
That's great.
And more easily.
Yeah.
That is great.
Okay.
Who else would like to ask a question?
Ideal Colab is actually the first paycheck I ever received as an intern, so that's crazy.
Thank you for that.
As a CEO in balancing, you know, risks and bets versus like standard operations for the business,
what is your process of building conviction behind a new bet when you're experiencing
resistance from your own organization?
Yeah, great question.
So part of what I described earlier around, moving people around and trying to cultivate
a team with lots of different perspectives and convictions, you actually, one of the
happy byproducts is it tends to generate internal debate, which I think is part of any healthy
organization.
You know, there's some fine line between healthy debate and sliding into a religious war.
And so crypto did kind of arouse some very primal feelings amongst a lot of people.
And definitely for a period of time slipped into that kind of religious war.
And I think you saw the evidence of that with many trad fi leaders speaking out in surprisingly
immature, but very loud ways about anti crypto stuff.
And I kind of felt like I knew I just had to be patient and just kind of keep going and
that the noise would pass.
And maybe this was people's way of feeling frustrated because something that they didn't
understand was gaining momentum and try to help people through that by not escalating
the religious war, and yeah, so it's allowing people to speak their mind, but stay calm
and continue to do their jobs.
And that included some jobs that were exploring Bitcoin and other crypto stuff that we were
working on.
So I think creating structurally to the extent that we had created this R&D lab, which was
actually something that was started by my father's super well established and around for decades,
our internal incubator, which was something that I institutionalized.
These are spaces where they're safe spaces to just go and do stuff that might fail.
And that's what they're supposed to do.
And if I say to people all the time, you know, if everything we do is successful in
our labs organization, we're not taking enough risk.
And we've got to have some fast, hopefully fast failures that happen there.
And otherwise, we're not pushing the limits enough.
So if you can get that institutionalized, then you create that much needed license for
people to do stuff that not everyone is on board with.
That's very interesting and very similar to the venture capital.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
If every company we invest in is a success, we didn't go broad enough.
We didn't take enough risk.
Yeah.
No, I took a page out of your book.
Thank you.
That's great.
Love it.
Let's see some hands.
If we're going to end up in a world where there's convergence between digital assets
and traditional assets, do you have a vision for what the crossover is going to be?
Like, what are we going to start doing in digital assets from TradFi?
What is TradFi going to start doing from digital assets?
Yeah.
In short, some of both.
You know, I'm more excited about the new stuff that we're going to bring to people and less
excited about trying to do fundamentally the same thing that we're doing just with different
technology underneath.
And I think there's -- but that's not -- it's not quite that simple, though, because if you
go back to the premise that I have that there is secular deflation in our business, all
the technology is going to have to change eventually.
And, you know, so we started moving our core operations to the cloud a bunch of years ago,
and we kind of had to mess around with it for a few years to figure out how to get it right
and make it super reliable and super safe.
And, you know, fortunately, you know, we had some low-risk situations that we put out there
and we learned a lot from those situations.
And, you know, so that was a big secular move for us to transition to that, and that's still
actually ongoing.
So you kind of can't help but ask, you know, is some of the capability that might someday
obsolete that web of reconciliations that is the industry today with a blockchain?
Yeah, you can -- you definitely see that.
It's just the path, the migration path, and I think, more importantly, the pace of that
migration path.
It's really -- I think you just have to kind of watch it and feel where it's going.
I don't know -- so I -- we're focused on building technology that is kind of our best
bet of where we think things will likely go near term, but, you know, have that longer
term view, and I think the surprise for me has been that it's closer in on that curve
of being in that bridge space, like doing things where there's a use case.
So with the stable coin, the tokenized money market fund where, you know, you need that
stable coin to participate in the DeFi world, but you have to -- if you want to earn interest
on it, then you need this, you know, digital version of an old world product.
So -- so I wish I could bring more science to this.
I think this is, you know, this is the hard question.
It is the quintessential question that I think everybody in this room has to try to -- try
to answer, but also try to drive it at the same time.
So we're the cause and the effect to some extent.
>> No, it's a difficult question, as you said, it's a very difficult question to answer.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Do you have another question?
>> You've exhausted the room.
>> We've exhausted the remote.
Oh, there's one more.
One more.
>> You've talked twice about -- or breakfast earlier about secular deflation, and my interpretation
of that was technology makes prices come down for everything.
Why, from externally, it seems that different financial institutions have different affinities
towards new technology, and I'm curious what determines an organization's appetite to
adopt things like crypto?
>> That's a great question, because it's a combination of time horizon and I think willingness
to take a smidgen bit of not so much regulatory, but, you know, people in the traditional
-- you know, they always talk about reputational risk.
So, you know, this was kind of the thing that got thrown around fidelity a lot during
some of the more contentious years.
You know, what's the reputational risk of us being in this space?
You know, even if we weren't doing really much of anything.
I mean, that when we did that first thing with the charitable gift fund where we took
the donations, we're taking donations from people who have just made their money from
Bitcoin.
I mean, it felt a little crazy to me, but it didn't feel crazy to have a lot of other
people.
And so, I think it's just personal, and I think -- I mean, here in this room, you guys
are all here because you're creative thinkers and you've got healthy risk appetites.
But in particularly in big companies, and I think particularly in financial services,
that doesn't really -- it's not a breeding ground.
I mean, if you -- sure, some investors, I mean, all the people who run portfolios or
hedge funds, I mean, these are all risk-seeking people, but they're doing it within a box
that's defined, and they're probably not thinking about -- in fact, I'm sure they're
not thinking about the nuts and bolts that underpin their ability to do what they do.
And I do think that's something that makes fidelity a little bit unique in that we really
elevate thinking about the nuts and bolts of the technology that underpins our ability
to do what we do because we've learned over the years that the more that technology that
we've been involved in building or tailoring or customizing to our use is what brings us
competitive advantage and sustainable competitive advantage because we can keep it up to date
and have the latitude to make the moves that we want to move make, but not -- that's not
really traditional financial services thinking based on what I see.
All right.
Well, Abby, this has been a great discussion.
Thank you again so much for coming and chatting with all of us.
It's really been fascinating.
We appreciate it.
Thanks for having me.
Thank you.